Notice Period: 3 Months

Highest Degree:



Senior Analyst Programmer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Software Programming, Core Java, J2EE, JSF, Servlets, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Java-Script, HTML, Ajax, CSS, XHTML, SVN, Git



Current Designation: Senior Analyst Programmer -Core Java Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Fidelity International - FIL Research (India)

Private Limited

Current Location: Noida

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Analyst Programmer, Tech Lead, Software Development, Application Development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Software Programming, Core Java, J2EE, JSF, Servlets, Spring MVC, Spring

Boot, Hibernate, Java-Script, HTML, Ajax, CSS, XHTML, SVN, Git

Verified: Phone Number 1 Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

#### Summary

An energetic, self-motivated Sr. Software Developer with 8 years and 6 months of experience in IT industry, have been involved in development, enhancements, maintenance and support of web Applications with specialization on J2EE/Java platform. Skill set include proficiency in programming knowledge with Java and J2EE components Client-Side Web technologies. Ability to learn new technologies faster and an excellent team player.

Excellent analytical and problem-solving skills combined with good communication and interpersonal skills.

Experience in working on Agile based development projects.

Ability to handle clients responsibly and spent 3 months at client site in USA.

Acted as coordinator between Onshore and Offshore team while being at client site.

Acted as a mentor and provided guidance, instruction, direction for new joiners in the team.

## Work Experience

Fidelity International - FIL Research (India) Private Limited as Senior Analyst Programmer -Core Java

Dec 2016 to Till Date

Fidelity International offers world class investment solutions and retirement expertise. It is a company, with the commitment and resources to provide the investment expertise, technology and service innovation needed to help clients achieve their financial goals. It invest USD \$272 billion globally on behalf of clients in Asia-Pacific, Europe, the Middle East, and South America. Its clients range from pension funds, central banks, sovereign wealth funds, large corporate, financial institutions, insurers and wealth managers, to private individuals.

# R Systems International Ltd as Senior Software Developer

Apr 2014 to Dec 2016

R Systems, founded in 1993, is a specialized IT Services & Solutions and IT-enabled Services provider catering to a wide range of global customers. It is endowed with some of the industry's highest quality certifications and standards, including CMMI Level 5, PCMM Level 5, ISO 27001:2013 and ISO 9001:2008. Its IT services and solutions span five major verticals which include Telecom & Digital Media, Banking & Finance, HealthCare, Manufacturing & Logistics, and Government Services.

# **Infosys Limited** as Senior Software Engineer Jul 2011 to Mar 2014

Infosys Limited (NASDAQ: INFY) is a global leader in consulting, technology and outsourcing. Many of the world's most successful organizations rely on Infosys to deliver measurable business value. Infosys provides business consulting, technology, engineering and outsourcing services to help clients in over 30 countries build tomorrow's enterprise.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from Punjabi University, Patiala in 2011

PG: in 0

#### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version Last Us	ed Experience
Java,JDK 7.0, J2EE, JSF, Servlets		
Hibernate, JDBC, JNDI,JSF,Spring MVC		
Java-Script, HTML, Ajax, CSS, XHTML		
RichFaces, Primefaces		
Eclipse, NetBeans		
Oracle, MySql, MSSQL, Microsoft windows		
Agile methodology (Scrum).		
Design Patterns		
spring boot		
Maven, Ant		
Bamboo, SVN, Bitbucket		
Teamcity, UDeploy, Jenkins		0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
WebServices(SOAP and REST)		
WebSphere, JBOSS		

### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Punjabi	Beginner			

#### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

#### **Work Authorization**

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

**Employment Status: Full time**